More bad hombres are about to get barbecued.
President Trump's turning up the heat on Venezuela
as he continues to bomb the ever-loving crap
out of narco-terrorists in the Caribbean,
killing more than 20 people.
The Washington Post is reporting
of U.S.
special ops helicopters operating within
roughly 90 miles of Venezuela's northern coast.
47 confirming he's authorized the CIA
to take action within the country.
What do you want to say?
Well, I don't want to tell you exactly,
but we are certainly looking at land now
because we've got the sea very well under control.
We've had a couple of days where there isn't a boat to be found.
And I view that as a good thing,
not a bad thing.
Does the CIA have authority to take out Maduro?
Oh, I don't want to answer a question like that.
That's a ridiculous question for me to be given.
Not really a ridiculous question,
but wouldn't it be a ridiculous question for me to answer?
But I think Venezuela's feeling heat.
It's a ridiculous question for me to answer,
but it's not a ridiculous question.
That's kind of brilliant.
Dana,
okay, we have to do a little victory lap
because you were here,
maybe it was four or five years ago,
when we posited taking out fentanyl labs in Mexico.
And people were saying,
oh my God, you can't do that.
That's unconstitutional.
I think he went one better.
They're like,
well,
there's the neocon,
saying it once again.
So one thing that this news just came out
that the Admiral overseeing the attacks against boats
in the Caribbean is stepping down.
Admiral
Alvin Holsey don't have a lot of information yet.
There's a New York Times piece.
I haven't read the whole thing,
but he's stepping down.
So this is,
I think he's stepping down as this is heating up.
Maybe he disagreed or maybe he,
well,
they didn't think he was the right person for it.
The secretary of war has thanked him for his service.
Is he overweight?
Doesn't look it.
Okay, all right, checking, checking.
Maduro himself, the leader of Venezuela,
I think in a way he wants this fight
because then it allows him to say to his people,
oh,
look,
the Yankee imperialists are coming after me.
He is the worst leader, he is the worst.
And he allows all this narco terrorism to happen
because he can't find,
there's no other way for him to fund the country.
And the woman who won the Nobel Prize last week,
she was the opposition leader
who has been trying to do good things for that country.
So I don't exactly know where this goes there.
It's interesting in terms of military law,
is this allowed?
Is it not?
You have some Republicans in the Congress saying,
are we gonna get a say in this?
But what president Trump has is the authority
to be able to say,
I need to protect my country from terrorists.
And he has deemed them as terrorists.
And so therefore, it seems to me,
he's got the authority to do it.
Tess,
I'm gonna ask you a difficult and challenging question.
Do you believe narco terrorists have rights?
On the high seas?
If a lawyer at the White House says no,
then I'm for it.
Let's go get them.
But this is more about regime change in Venezuela.
We have 10% of our naval power in the region.
We have a destroyer fleet.
We have F
-35s there.
And now we have these helicopters which are used
for Green Berets, Delta and Special Forces.
So this is serious stuff.
The CIA has been unleashed.
We have a $50 million bounty on this guy's head.
Trump's now considering strikes on Venezuelan soil.
And so we're engaged in what we like to call
some friendly gunboat diplomacy.
And the New York Times reported that
we've been in negotiations with the regime.
And the regime said,
we will give you dominant stakes
in our oil, our gold and our mineral wealth.
And we've agreed to cut ties with China and Russia.
And Rubio and Trump said no.
So that tells me there's gonna be major action
against Maduro pretty soon.
And you never know how this goes.
These things in Latin America can go sideways,
but also they could be layups.
And if it is a layup and Maduro is deposed,
we're basically Monroe doctoring.
We call it the Dunro doctoring out of Latin America,
of China and Russia.
And what does that do after the successful strikes
against the Iranian regime?
That basically takes this big pile of deterrence
and shoves it right in Taiwan's face,
right in Ukraine's face.
And Trump is wielding a lot of power internationally after.
Jessica, is this just another example
of toxic masculinity now being exported beyond our borders?
I'm sure the group chat is crazy
for the guys in charge of this.
Hopefully not on signal anymore.
Hopefully those don't come out.
I remember the day the first boat was struck.
And Jesse told me, do you wanna be on the side
of narco terrorists?
And I said, no, not especially.
Like, let's see where this goes.
And now we're up to multiple votes.
And it's not just Venezuelan boats.
The Colombians say that one of the boats was theirs
and that two Colombian nationals,
I think two or three,
were murdered when they were struck
and that they weren't drug traffickers.
Now, do I know if that's the case or not?
I'm not sure, but there is a reason that we're-
Don't let that stop you.
Well, don't let the constitution stop you.
And there's supposed to be oversight.
As Dana mentioned, there are Republicans
and Democrats alike saying, you know,
this is turning into more of a habit than
just striking one boat and that we are
supposed to have a say in this.
And historically speaking,
and I know you're going to make fun of me,
but that's why I come to work every day.
Drug traffickers were considered criminals with due process rights.
And this is the conversation we've been
having as well about undocumented people
in this country who also have due process
rights as Antonin Scalia affirmed.
And
I don't know if it's a good precedent or road to be
going down that he's essentially starting some degree
of war without Congress being able to see anything.
The intel community,
the people who chair these committees
are not getting to see what it is,
that,
you know,
the basis for the actions that they're taking.
And I don't think that you're going to be that
comfortable with the idea of them going into Venezuelan
land without there being any verification besides,
you know,
Trump and Pete Hegcess said so.
Well, we'll have to wait and see on that.
Check your tax.
Yes. I, um,
hi, Emily.
I know, I know, I know.
I was,
I was going to,
I wanted to ask you about the one hundred and
seventy five thousand Americans applying for jobs.
OK. But I wasn't sure if you wanted to talk about that or this.
Why do you care what she wants?
You literally force whatever topic you want down my throat.
That is true.
I'm his favorite.
Why is that the only reason?
I have to respond to this.
The president can can obviously direct covert CIA
operations under the National Security Act of 1947.
All he has to do is issue a presidential finding,
which basically is a classified briefing he gives to
the gang of eight via notify in Congress in that way.
And then they can they authorize the funding
through the House and the Senate Appropriations
Committees on the Intelligence.
And the whole point is that if they wanted to withdraw funding,
go
ahead.
But you're right.
There is an opacity involved and a third option involved.
And that's for the sanctity and security of
our executive branch in addition to Americans.
And I think it's interesting the arguments that,
oh,
this might destabilize Venezuela because to me,
the ostrich head in the sand that we suffered
from under the Obama administration and the Biden
administration's only emboldened terrorists.
We I don't argue that we can put them in
the criminal drug running neat box very
neatly because they have pivoted significantly
since President Trump has taken office.
And now they are into a whole host of illicit
industries pouring over through Canada
and taking advantage of their loopholes there.
They're raiding avocado farms,
not avocados,
that liquid gold.
And the whole the whole point is that these guys,
if you think for one second that
they're going to let one dollar of their billions
upon billions of income gained illicitly every
year to be diverted or extinguished in any way,
they will fight to the death.
But at least
have faith in our administration that
we aren't going to take it lying down.
And that 175
years what I love about it,
you guys remember the dams when they put out the chooser fighter
and bless them for trying.
But they're like old people hopping around and someone's doing
a tick tock video.
And here they actually have I says
the Department of Homeland Security,
it says choose your mission.
And when it talks about the brave men and women that are signing
up in record numbers now to defend and support this nation,
like if you want to be an attorney for the closers,
for the resolute,
for those who represent the USA,
for those that are officers,
for the enforcers,
for the brave,
for those who fight to keep America safe.
In direct contrast to the names that the
Democrat leadership and elected officials,
these congressmen and senators call them Nazis and fascists.
No, these are the brave.
They're the ones that I take my hat off to
and thank them for their service.
All right.